If you all want to know about Wealth Ashor Plus Plan of Aditya Birla Sun Life
Insurance Company Limited
in detail then check the description of today's video.
You will find the link to the Wealth Ashor Plus
Plan video in the description of the video.  As
you all know that every day every video on the channel
comes as per your questions, suggestions and comments.  So
stay connected to the channel and for that
like the video, share it,
subscribe to the channel and turn on all the notification bells
because only through that
you will be able to get the latest updates on time.  Hello
everyone, you all are very welcome.
You're watching You the Real.  I am your
host and friend Amit Raj Sharma.  In today's
video, we will learn about the Wealth Aspire Plan of
Aditya Birla Sun Life Insurance
Company Limited as per the comment of Mr.
But before that we
will tell you that Unit Linked Plan is a
subject to market risk.  Whatever
money you invest here, you have
market related risk for which
you are solely responsible.
Therefore, you should
invest only with proper planning.  Under the Wealth Aspire plan,
you get two plan options
and 19 different fund options.  You will
choose the plan option, choose the fund option,
invest the premium and
whatever fund value is available at the end of the policy term will be given to
you as maturity.
With this, the S per the plan option will remain
within your life insurance plan.   We will
understand further how the benefits will work.  Now watch the video
in full screen so that you can understand the eligibility criteria of Wealth Aspire Plan of Aditya Builders
Sun Life Insurance Company Limited.  The
first option in the plan is the Classic option.   The
minimum entry age limit for classic options is
30 days.  That means if your
child is 30 days old then
you will be able to avail this option for him.  If you
take a premium payment term of 5 years, then
people up to 50 years of age will be able to avail this option.  If the
premium payment term is 6 years or 7 years, then a
person of maximum 55 years of age will be
able to avail this option.  If the
premium payment term is 8 years or more, then
people up to 65 years of age can take the Classic option.  The
maturity age range is
18 to 70 years for premium payment term of 5 to 7 years.  If the
premium payment term is 8 years or more,
then the maturity age limit is 18 to 75 years.  The
second option is the assured option.
If you opt for the assured option, the minimum
entry age limit is 18 years and the
premium payment term is from 5 to 8 years,
so people up to 45 years of age will be
able to avail this option.  If the
premium payment term is 9 years or more, then
people up to 50 years of age will be able to avail this option.  The
maturity age range under the Ash option is from
28 years to 60
years.  Policy Term Option:
With both the plan options,
you get the option of policy term ranging from 10 years to 40 years.  The
premium payment term
option available for both the plans ranges from
5 years to 40 years.  The
minimum base
premium limit is ₹400 per year.
If you pay the premium in half-yearly installments, the minimum premium limit is
₹45,000 and for quarterly and monthly
installments, the minimum premium
limit is ₹50,000.  If
your age at the time of taking the plan is between 61 years to 65 years,
then you will have to pay a base premium of ₹5 lakh annually.  The
minimum sum assured
limit is ₹4 lakh i.e.
10 times the annual premium.  The minimum limit for top-up premium is
₹5,000.
On which a locking period of 5 years
is applicable.  This means that
you will not be able to add top-up premium in the last 5 years of the policy.
Let us now know
about the benefits of Wealth S plan of Aditya Birla Sun Life Insurance Company Limited.  If you have
chosen the Classic option, then the parcel withdrawals made in the
last 2 years will be deducted from the sum assured to calculate the death benefit.
Which last 2 years?  The
right before the date of death will be compared
with the fund value,
whichever is higher of the two will be
given to the nominee as death benefit, the policy will be closed.
Suppose you have paid the top-up
premium, then in such a case the
fund value of the top-up premium will be
compared with the sum measured of the top-up premium,
whichever is
higher of the two will be given to the nominee
and after that the policy will be closed.
So this is your death benefit in case of classic option.
If you have chosen the assured option, then
in case of the assured option, the
death benefit which is the sum assured, if there is
any top-up premium along with it, then the top-up
sum assured will also be paid to the nominee,
after that all future premiums will be
waived and the policy will continue, as a
result the maturity benefit i.e. the
fund value will be received by the nominee here, that is, the
minimum death benefit,
that sum assured, will be received lump sum,
after that no future premium will have to be paid
and the maturity benefit will also be
received by the nominee and we know that the
maturity benefit in a ULIP plan is the
available fund value on the date of maturity.
In this plan you get guaranteed addition.
It depends on the premium band.
If your premium is of Band One.  Is the
premium limit of Right Band One
given here?  So,
from the 11th year to the 15th year of the policy,
you will get a guaranteed addition of 0.2% of your average fund value every year.  This
means that it will keep
accumulating in the policy and will be received only
on maturity.  If your premium
is of Band 2, then you will continue to get 0.6%
from the sixth year to the 10th year of the policy.
Guaranteed addition of Average Fund Value will continue to accrue to the policy.
From the 11th year to the 15th year,
0.9% will be given and from the 16th year onwards, 1% of the
average fund value of 12 months will be
given every year.
If your annual premium is ₹5 lakh
or more, then you will fall in Band 3
and in such a case,
0.6% of the average fund value within 12 months will continue to
accrue in the policy from the sixth year to the tenth year.  From the 11th year to the
15th year, 0.9% of that average fund value
and after the 16th year or from the 16th year onwards,
1% of the average fund value will be added to the policy every year.  As
soon as your policy
reaches its 10th year, then in the
10th year of the policy and thereafter
in every 5-year gap, if
your premium is of Band 1, then a guaranteed addition of
2% of the basic premium that you would have paid in 60 months will be
added.  It will
start from the 10th year of the policy and will continue to be given at an interval of every 5 years.  If
your premium is in Band 2 or Band 3, then 2.5% of the basic
premium paid by you in the last 60 months will continue to
accrue to the policy as a guaranteed addition.   It will
start from the end of the 10th year of the policy
and will be available at every 5-1 year interval.
Let us now know about the investment options of Wealth Aspire Plan of Aitya Birla Sun
Life Insurance Company.
So the first option here is the Smart Option
which is a combination of two funds.  That means there will be a
combination of equity and debt.   There
is Maximizer Fund for Equity and
Income Advantage Fund for Day.  There
are three categories of risk profiles.  Conservative,
Moderate and Aggressive.  Here it is written
years to maturity.  That is,
how many years are left for maturity is written here.
If you have taken the aggressive option and
only 5 years are left for maturity.
So in such a situation there will be 0% investment in equity.
If you have
6 to 10 years left for maturity, then
15% of your investment will be allocated towards equity i.e. maximizer fund.
If there are 11 to 15
years left for maturity, then 35%. If there are
16 to 20 years left for maturity and you have taken the aggressive option, then
50% of the investment you are making will be allocated in equity.
If 21 to 30
years are left for maturity then 65%, if
31 to 40 years are left for maturity then
80% of the portfolio will be
in equity and the remaining 20% ​​will be in Income
Advantage Fund, you can pause here and
read the rest, I have explained it to you in a simple
way, you get Systematic Transfer
Investment option, in this
whatever premium you pay, first it will
go into Liquid Plus Fund, after that on
monthly or weekly basis
it will keep getting transferred to your chosen fund.
According to whatever ratio you choose.  Right?   The
third option here is Return
Optimizer.  In this, first of all your
premium will be invested in the Maximizer Fund.
When investment is made in Maximizer Fund, when its minimum growth is
10% or more, then the
units of growth or gain will be transferred to
Income Advantage Fund so that the risk of
Maximizer Fund which is equity based can be
managed here.  The fourth
option is the self-manage option, in
which there are 18 fund options
within the plan, you will choose any fund from them and you will
manage everything yourself, you will
also be able to switch from one fund to another,
okay, when it comes to parcel withdrawal,
we know that if you take a plan for a minor, then
you will be able to withdraw only when you are at least 18 years of age and the first
5 years of the policy are the locking period, only after that
you will be able to withdraw.  Both conditions apply.  You
can make a partial withdrawal of minimum ₹5000.  But the fund balance
after withdrawal should remain equal to the annual base
premium.  You will not be able to withdraw more than
25% of your average fund value within a maximum of 1 year.
Let us
now know about the charges of Wealth Aspire Plan of Aitya Birls Sunlife
Insurance Company Ltd.  The
first
charge you will incur is the premium
allocation charge.  If the premium is of Band One then
7% of the premium will be charged in the first year.   If the
premium is in Band Two then it is 6% and
your premium is coming in the category of Band Three.  This
means that if you are paying more than ₹5 lakh annually, a
premium allocation charge of 4.5% will be
levied.  If the premium is Band One from the second year of the policy, then
5% will be charged.  If you are
paying premium for Band 2 category then it will be
4%, if your premium is for Band 3 category then it will be
3%.  This is the percentage of premium
written.  If you pay top-up premium,
you will be charged 2% of the top-up premium as
premium allocation charge.  The
policy discontinuation charge can range
from ₹1000 to a maximum of ₹6000.
It will vary depending on the year in which you are discontinuing the policy and the premium you were paying.
You are also charged policy administration charges.  Its
maximum limit has been fixed at ₹6000 per year.
What could be the minimum
?  It is written on the top of the screen.  You will
see that.  You will also incur mortality charges.
It will depend on what your age is.
How much risk cover are you taking?
What is your lifestyle? What plan option are you choosing?
Extra? Okay, now we will know
about the fund management charges.
We will also know about the fund. The first one is Liquid
Plus Fund. The company launched Liquid Plus Fund
on 9 March 2012.
This is a fund of very low risk category because there will be
no equity exposure here. So its
average rate of return from the date of its
inception till now has been
6.46%.  Fund management charge will be
1% of the annual average fund value.  The
second fund option here is Income
Advantage.  The Income Advantage Fund launched by the company was
launched on August 22, 2008.
This means that the Income Advantage Fund
also has a very low risk profile.  This means that
you do not have equity exposure here also.
Its FM i.e. Fund
Management Charge has been
1% of the annual average fund value.  The fact sheet
states that the average rate of return from August 22, 2008 till date is 7.46%.  The
third option
here is Ashor Fund.  Ashor Fund was
launched by the company on 12 September 2005.  This fund also has a
very low risk profile.  That means there is
no risk in it.  This is very low.  So in
a way we can consider it safe.
Fund management charges will remain the same.
1% of the annual average fund value.  Its average rate of
return has been around 8%.  The fourth fund
option is Protector Fund.  From the name itself it is clear
that it is a debt category fund.  So it is
obvious that this fund belongs to the low risk category.
Its date of inception was 22 March
2001.  That is, the company
launched this fund on 22 March 2001.  Since then,
its average rate of return has been
8.0%.
Here you will be charged fund management charge of 1% of the annual average fund value.  The
number five option here is
builder fund.  The Builder Fund was
launched by the company on 22 March 2001.
This fund is in the low risk category.
You will be charged a fund management charge of 1% of the annual average fund value.  The
average rate of return from March 22,
2001 till date has been
9.54%.  The number six option here is the
unattached fund.  The company also launched the NHER Fund
on March 22, 2001.  This is a medium
risk category profile as
you will get equity exposure here.  So, that
means the chances of returns will also be higher
because the risk is higher.
Fund management charge will be 1.25% of the annual average fund value.   The
average rate of return has
been 10.16%.  Number seven here is the
Creator Fund.  The Creator Fund was launched by the company
on 23 February 2004.  Now the Creator
Fund also has a medium risk profile, that is, there will be
medium risk in this fund.
Fund management charge will be 1.25% of the annual average fund value.  The
average rate of return since February 23, 2004 has
been 11.29%.  Number eight is PayCap
Nifty Index Fund which was
launched by the company on September 24, 2015.  This is a high
risk category fund as the
equity exposure here will be at least up to 80%.
Fund management charge will be 1.25% of the annual average fund value.  Its
average rate of return has
been 11.62%.  Fund number nine here is the
asset allocation fund.  The Asset Allocation Fund was
launched by the company on 24 September 2015.  The
fund management charge is the same in this fund also.
1.25% of the annual average fund value
as this fund is also a high risk category
fund.  This means that at
least 80% of your money will remain in equity.  Its average rate of
return has
been 10.39%.  The 10th fund
is Magnifier Fund which was
launched by the company on 12 August 2004.
This fund is in the high risk category.  Here also the fund
management charge will be
1.35% of the annual average fund value
because up to 100% of the premium can be invested in equity.   The
average rate of return has been 12.38%.   The
number 11 fund option here is Maximizer
Fund which was launched by the company on June 12, 2007.
This fund is in the high risk category.  So,
fund management charge of 1.35% of the annual average fund value will be levied.
Its average rate of return from June 12, 2007 till date has been
10.58%.  The fund option number is 12.
Multiplier was launched by the company on 30 October 2007.
This fund is in the high risk category.
So the fund management charge will be
1.35% of the average fund value annually.
Its average rate of return has
been 12.58% since the date of
inception.  Right?  Fund option number 11
here is Super 20 Fund.  Super 20 Fund was
launched by the company on 6 July 2009.
This fund is in the high risk category.  This means that
equity exposure can be up to 100%.
Fund management charge will be
1.35% of the average fund value annually.  The average rate of
return has
been 12.03%.  The information is available in the fact sheet of the fund.   That's where
I'm telling you.  Pure
Equity Fund was launched by the company on 9 March 2012.
Fund management charge will be 1.35% of the annual average fund value.
This is a fund with a high risk profile.  Its average rate
of return
was 14.78%.  From 9 March 2012 to 28
February 25 i.e. till the end of February 2025.
Number 15 here is Value &
Momentum which the company launched on March 9, 2012.  It is an
ICE category fund.  Its
average rate of return
was 11.8%.  Fund management charges will be
1.35% of the four-yearly average fund value every year.
MAC Fund is Fund No. 16 MAC
Fund was launched by the company on 15 February 2019.
This is also a high risk category fund.
So the FMC i.e. fund management
charge will be 1.35% of the annual average fund value
every year.  Its average rate of return has
been 8.73%.  The number 17 fund is an
ESG fund.  The ESG fund was launched by the company on
November 21, 2023.  It is a high risk
category fund.
Fund management charge will be 1.35% of the annual average fund value.  The
average rate of return has been
8.29%.  Fund number 18 is
Small Cap Fund, here the name itself shows that
this varier falls under this category of fund.
Here,
fund management charge of 1.35% of the annual average fund value will be levied.  Its
date of inception is 20 November 2023.
Its average rate of return has been around 2%.
Because the
market has fallen very rapidly in the last few times.   The
small cap fund has also performed negatively.
You know this thing.  Discontinued
Policy Fund is the fund
into which
all units are transferred when you discontinue the policy.
This fund was launched by the company on January 1, 2014.
Very low risk profile
as there is no equity exposure.
Your money goes into government security corporate bound.
Fund management charge is 0.50% of the annual average fund value.   The
average rate of return
is 5.53%.  You are also subject to switch charges and partial
withdrawal charges.
₹50 on request, this can go up to a maximum of ₹500 on
request as per the
policy document.  Now
what is the main thing in this plan?  That is its
unshared option.  Apart from the classic option, there are
other plans available as well.  So
if you take the short option, you pay a
premium of ₹1 lakh annually at the age of 30 years.
Paying premium for 15 years.  I am
taking a positive term of 30 years
and investing all the money in a maximizer fund.
So the life cover will be at least
10 times the annual premium i.e. ₹1 lakh.
If the
average rate of return is 8%, then here we are being
told that brother, we can
get ₹570153.  If the rate of return is 4%
then you can
get ₹2193000.  If
something happens at maturity, say during the premium payment
term, then all future premiums will be
waived.  The nominee will definitely get at least ₹1 lakh
and later on, maturity
benefit can be received as it is.  Because it
is a ULIP plan.  No matter how much calculation you do, there is
no benefit.  Because it is
subject to market risk.  The
returns can be seen as per the performance of the fund.  That's why
I
explained the average rate of return of the fund and
also the date of inception in the video.  I
hope you have watched the video carefully.
Thanks for watching the video till the end.
Please like and share the video
and subscribe to the channel.
Thank you.
[music]